Guide to the Harwood Family Papers, 1722-1962
Department of Special Collections
Harwood Family Papers,
1722-1962
Special Collections M0206
Harwood family.
2 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Wilson Franklin Harwood, 1969.
Biographical Note
Over his lifetime, Andrew Allen Harwood (1802-1884), great grandson of Benjamin Franklin, kept letters and notes of interest and autographs in a collection known as ODDS & ENDS. He willed it to his grandson, Thomas Triplett Hunter Harwood. In the year 1940 it passed into the hands of his nephew, A. A. Harwood's great grandson, Wilson Franklin Harwood (Stanford '35).
A. A. Harwood's career in the Navy started with his appointment as Midshipman on the gun-brig Saranac in 1818. He retired with the rank of Rear Admiral in 1874. For this reason, much of the material he put into his odds and ends was navy connected.
After 1940, W. F. Harwood added other items of interest that had come into the possession of various branches of the family over time.
Much of the added documentation concerns George Spencer Wilson, maternal grandfather of W. F. Harwood. G. S. Wilson (1842-1897) from boyhood was in the military service. In 1861 he started as a corporal in the Indiana Volunteers; at the time of his death he was Major and Assistant Adjutant General, U.S. Army.
Another source was the archives of Lee Lewis Harwood (Stanford '38). Her father, Winford Lee Lewis (1878-1943), a graduate of Stanford University and a chemist, had kept a few letters from Jordan, Hoover, Wilbur, and others.
Many references will be found in the more recent papers to the parents of W. F. Harwood: Franklin Bache Harwood (1876-) and Margaret Spencer Wilson Harwood (1883-1964).
Scope and Content
Letters, notes, autographs, portraits, and other materials collected by the Harwood Family over a period of two hundred-fifty years. Much of the early materials, including Revolutionary War era materials, are navy and military service related. Later materials include letters from major political, financial, and literary figures. Correspondents include Herbert Hoover, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Ray Lyman Wilbur, Pearl S. Buck, and Carl Sandburg. Also included are engravings, photographs, and autographs of historical figures.
INDEX
Oversized items listed at the end of the guide have not been indexed.
M206
HARWOOD FAMILY PAPERS
Abercrombie, Gen. 2 30 36
Abercromby, Lt. Gen. 2 30 49
Abbot, C.W. Jr. 1 20 165
Adamic, Louis 3 31 41
Alger, Horatio Jr. 3 31 62
Allen, Chas. H 2 28 3
Allen, M. 1 15 108
Arago, F. 1 17 42
Aretresa, Il Fonte 2 30 42
Armstrong, R.B. 2 28 39, 2 28 40
Arnold, Benedict 1 1 1
Astor, Nancy 3 31 26
Atherton, Gertrude 3 31 25, 3 31 30, 3 31 34
Babbage, Charles 1 7 41
Babcock, H.P. 2 30 62
Bache, Alexander Dallas 1 17 138, 2 29 2 (?), 3 31 80
Bache, Mrs. 1 1 6, 1 5 29, 1 6 33, 1 6 36-38, 1 17 40, 2 30 59
Bache, Richard 1 1 7
Bainbridge, Wm. 1 4 21, 1 5 24
Baird, Spencer F. 1 12 83
Banks, N.P. 1 12 86
Barney, John A. 3 31 1
Barron, J. 1 8 54, 3 31 9
Bart, Sir Thomas Munro 2 30 10
Bartram, Wm. 1 1 2-5
Bates, Edward 1 14 104-6
Benet, Wm. Rose 2 27 254
Beresford, William-Carr 2 30 21
Bernard, Lt. Gen. Simon 1 6 35, 3 31 57
Biddle, James 2 30 27
Boncicault, Dion 3 31 66
Booth, Edwin 1 20 161
Boskerk, Van J. 2 28 23
Bourke, John G. 1 20 163
Boyer, B.M. 3 31 49
Brander, James 2 29 15
Breckinridge, J.C. 1 20 162
Bremer, Federika 3 31 38
Bronk, Detlev 2 27 259
Brown, Allan D. 2 28 1
Brown, Hugh G. 1 21 179
Brown, Samuel 1 4 22
Buck, Pearl S. 2 27 252
Bufano, Beniamino 2 26 245
Bunce, F.M. 2 28 3
Burnet, R. Douglass 1 24 208
Burnett 1 5 28
Burnett, Frances Hodgson 3 31 36, 3 31 51
Burnett, J.C. 1 21 180
Burnett, Jere 1 17 136
Burnett, Samuel 1 17 136
Burnett, Vivian 3 31 59
Burr, Aaron 1 2 11
Bush, V. 3 31 94
Cable, Geo. W. 2 25 221
Cadman 3 31 40
Cadrington, Sir Edward 2 30 23
Calhoun, John C. 1 8 47, 1 8 49, 1 8 51, 2 30 45, 3 31 92
Candolle, Augustin Pyrame de 2 29 2
Cantwell, J.C. 2 28 44
Casy, Commander 2 29 12
Charles II 2 30 17
Chauncey, J. 2 4 23, 1 6 31
Choate, Joseph H. 3 31 31
Churchill, Winston 2 27 55
Cisco, John J. 1 13 93
Clay, Henry 3 31 92
Cleveland, Francis F. 1 19 155, 3 31 70
Cleveland, Grover 3 31 70
Cochrane, Lord 2 30 37
Collingwood, Cuthbert 2 30 50
Collingwood, Lord 2 30 38
Cook, Capt. James 2 30 20
Cooke, A. 1 15 108
Cooke, G.F. 1 21 183
Coolidge, Calvin 3 31 47
Cooper, James Fenimore 1 8 53
Corbin, Guy C. 2 29 7
Corbin, Henry C. 1 21 178
Cox 1 4 18, 19
Crane, W.M. 3 31 65
Cruikshank, George 3 31 22
Cumberland, Duke of 2 30 46
Curdg, Maj. Gen. 1 23 200
Curtis, Geo. Wm. 1 17 137
Dalgren, John A. 1 12 81
Danberry, Charles 3 31 85
Davezac, August 1 6 34
Decatur, Stephen 3 31 9
DeHart, W.C. 2 28 11, 2 28 13-15
DeLaffre, A.A. 1 24 212
Dickens, Charles 1 16 124, 1 16 125
Dickerson, Mahlon 3 31 71
Dickins, F.W. 2 28 2
Dill, Thomas T. 1 21 172
Dobbin, James C. 1 11 76, 2 29 5, 2 29/6
Donkin, Lt. Gen. Sir R.S. 2 30 6
Dorr, J.W. 1 7 43
Doyle, W.E. 1 15 117, 1 19 152
Duane, D. 3 31 24
Duane, Richard B. 1 14 100
Duane, William J. 1 9 56, 1 11 79, 1 8 142, 2 30 90, 3 31 21
Duer, Wm. 1 2 9
Dupont, S.F. 1 13 90, 3 31 75
Edward, Duke of Kent 2 30 33
Egbert, Harry C. 1 20 170
Eisenhower, Dwight D. 2 27 258
Eisenhower, Mrs. 2 27 258
Elliott, Jesse D. 1 4 18, 19
Emerson, R.W. 3 31 90
Everett, E. 3 31 79
Farnham, John 1 5 28
Farragut, David E. 1 8 55, 1 8 59, 1 9 63, 1 16 118, 1 16 119
Farrand, Max 2 26 241
Faxen, Wm. 1 13 94
Fee, Jerome 2 25 219
Fischer, Emil 2 25 215
Fisher, J.E. 1 20 167
Foote, A.H. 3 31 74
Fosdick, Harry 2 27 248
Fox, G.V. 1 12 89
Franklin, Benjamin 1 1 2-5, 1 1 7, 1 2 8, 2 30 3, 2 30 43, 3 31 2
Franklin, Elizabeth 1 1 6
Fraser, Lt. Gen. Alexander MacKenzie 2 30 24
Friedel, Frank 1 14 107
Gage, Lyman 2 28 9
Gahagan, Helen 2 26 245
Garfield, James A. 1 18 145, 2 30 52, 3 31 46
Garibaldi, G. 1 16 123
Garrison, Oswald 1 23 199
Gilder, R.W. 1 20 160, 2 25 217, 2 25 222, 3 31 78
Gilmore, J.C. 1 21 189
Gilpin, J.B. 1 6 32
Goethals, Geo. W. 2 25 219
Goldsborough, Louis M. 3 31 73
Gordon, Chas. 3 31 42
Gordon, W.H. 1 21 185
Gould, Dr. 1 17 131
Graham, John 1 10 69
Grant, U.S. 2 30 83, 3 31 69
Gresham, W.O. 1 19 154, 1 21 176, 1 22 192
Griswold, Alexander V. 3 31 50
Haenel, A. 1 12 88
Hall, Basil 3 31 19
Hall, David 2 28 11
Halliburton, Richard 3 31 33
Hamilton, Alexander 1 2 9, 2 30 91
Hamlet, O.C. 2 28 8
Hancock, John 2 30 44
Harding, W.G. 2 25 225
Harris, Ira 2 28 5
Hartley, David 1 2 8
Harwood, A.A. 1 4 21, 22, 1 5 24-27, 1 5 29, 1 6 31, 1 6 33, 1 6 34-39, 1 7 40, 1 7 42, 1 7 44-46, 1 8 49,50, 1 9 56-63, 1 10 66, 1 10 68,69, 1 10 71-77, 1 10 79, 1 12 83-85, 1 13 90,94, 1 14 98, 1 14 100,01, 1 14 103-06, 1 15 114, 1 16 119-21, 1 16 124, 1 16 127, 1 17 130, 1 17 134, 1 17 139, 1 18 140-42, 1 18 149, 2 29 8,9, 2 29 12, 2 30 2, 2 30 87, 3 31 18, 3 31 56, 3 31 95,96, 3 35 all
Harwood, Bessie 1 19 155
Harwood, F.B. 2 28 1-9, 2 28 11-23, 2 28 25-48, 2 30 58 (?)
Harwood, Frank 1 9 61, 1 10 66, 1 10 70, 1 11 78, 3 31 52
Harwood, John Edward 2 29 1, 3 32 all
Harwood, Miss E.F. 1 20 160,61
Harwood, Mrs. 1 2 12,13
Harwood, Mrs. F.B. 2 26 229, 2 26 238,39 2 27 249, 2 27 250, 2 27 252-54, 2 27 257
Harwood, Mrs. Lee 2 27 260
Harwood, Mrs. M.B. 1 10 65, 1 19 150,51,
Harwood, Mrs. Margaret B. 2 27 248
Harwood, Sally F. 2 26 230
Harwood, Sarah 2 25 225, 2 25 228
Harwood, W.F. 2 25 223, 2 26 232, 2 26 240-42, 2 27 251, 2 27 259, 3 31 33
Hayes, Mrs. R.B. 1 18 141
Hayes, Rutherford B. 1 18 141, 3 31 23
Henry, Joseph 1 17 138
Hershel, Sir John 1 7 41
Hill, I.H. 3 31 89
Hill, I.W. 1 10 68
Holmes, O.W. 1 17 131
Hood, Alexander 2 30 19
Hoover, Herbert 2 26 230, 2 26 243, 2 27 246, 2 27 249
Hopkinson, Fran 1 2 10
Horatio, Viscount Nelson 2 30 8
Howard, Chas. 2 30 47
Howe, Earl 2 30 31
Howe, Lord Viscount 2 30 18
Howells, W.D. 2 25 218
Howland, W.S. 2 28 26
Huddart, Capt. Jos. 2 30 51
Hull, Isaac 1 4 16
Huntington 2 25 220
Huntington, Marian 2 30 82
Huntington, Samuel 1 1 1
Hutchins, Rob't M. 2 27 250
Ingraham, Capt. 1 6 39
James, Wm. 1 19 156, 1 25 218
Janauschek, Fanny 3 31 48
Jefferson, Thomas 1 2 14
Jervis, John 2 30 9, 2 30 22
Joinville, Prince de 1 13 97
Jones, Wm. H. 1 19 159
Jordan, David Star 2 25 226, 2 25 227
KalaKaua, David 3 31 67
Kelton, J.C. 1 18 146
Kennedy, John P. 1 9 62
Kilgore, H.M. 3 31 93
Knight, Sir Edward Hawke 2 30 16
Knox, Henry 3 31 4
LaMont, David S. 1 21 172, 1 21 177
Lavallee 1 7 42
Lawrence, James 2 30 77, 3 31 11
Leahr, Chas. 1 17 133
Leslie, E. 1 7 44
Lewis, W. Lee 2 25 226, 2 25 227, 2 26 231, 2 26 233-36, 2 26 243, 44, 2 27 246
Lincoln, Abraham 1 12 81, 1 12 87, 1 14 102, 3 31 28
Lion, Chas. 2 29 11
Livingston, Edward 3 31 20
Lomax, L.L. 3 31 72
Long, John C. 1 11 74
Long, John D. 2 28 4
Longfellow, Henry W. 1 9 60, 2 29 14
Louis, Phillippe J. 2 30 25
Luce, Steven B. 1 17 139, 3 34 all (?)
Luce, Wm. 1 13 96
Macdonough 3 31 13
MacKau, Baron de 1 8 50
MacLeish, Archibald 3 31 27
Madison, Dolley 1 2 12, 13
Madison, James 2 30 80
Marshall, J.M. 2 24 208
Masher, Theo. 1 21 182
Mason, J.Y. 1 8 48, 1 9 57
McClernard, John A. 1 12 85
McClune, A. 1 23 198
McCulloch, Hugh 3 31 77
McNear, E. Denman 3 31 34
McNear, Geo. P. 2 25 224
Merrell, Jno. P. 2 28 3, 2 28 5
Michael, Wm. 1 15 109
Middleton, Henry 3 31 15
Miller, A.O. 1 20 171
Millikan, Robert A. 3 31 29
Monroe, Jas. 1 4 20, 2 30 89 (?)
Montague, H.J. 3 31 64
Morris, Chas. 1 4 16, 1 10 65, 1 11 73
Morris, F.H. 2 28 6
Moultrie, Maj. Gen. Wm. 2 30 7
Murel, L. 2 29 8
Murray, Sir George 2 30 40
Napolean III 1 9 64, 3 31 54
Nelson, Lord 2 30 14, 2 30 30, 2 30 34
Nesselrode, Chancellor Count 1 10 67
Newman, Capt. James 2 30 13
Nicholson, J.J. 3 31 17
Nicolay, John G. 1 12 89
Nuckles, J.M. 1 21 186
Ogelthorpe, Gen. 2 30 11
Pacha, Rechid 1 10 67
Paget, Henry Wm. 2 30 39
Parker, Theodore 2 29 4
Pavlova, Anna 2 25 224
Perry, C.G. 3 31 82
Perry, M.C. 1 7 45, 3 31 81
Perry, Oliver H. 2 30 75, 3 31 12
Phillips, John 3 31 87
Phister, Nat 1 22 195
Pickering, Timothy 3 31 6
Picton, Sir Thomas 2 30 28
Pinckney, Thomas 3 31 5,6
Pinkney, Charles C. 3 31 3
Pisma, Il Fonte Crane la 2 30 41
Pitcher, U.L. 1 21 188
Polhill, George 2 30 86
Porter, David 1 5 25, 2 30 73, 3 31 10
Powell 1 8 48, 1 8 54, 1 8 55, 3 33 all
Preble, Edward 3 31 8
Rice, Dr. 2 25 221
Rice, Mr. 1 17 133
Roath, W.D. 2 28 15, 2 28 21, 2 28 23, 2 28 25
Rockefeller, Nelson A. 2 27 251
Rooke, Sr. Geo. 2 30 26
Roosevelt, F.D. 2 25 228, 2 30 88
Roosevelt, Theo. 1 22 196
Ross, Sir John 2 30 15
Ross, W.G. 2 28 27, 2 28 33, 2 28 42, 2 28 47
Rossiter, Thomas R. 1 16 121, 1 16 125
Russell, Andrew H. 1 23 205
Sabine, Major 3 31 84
Sandburg, Carl 2 26 238,39,40,42
Scott, Mr. 2 27 247
Scott, Winfield 2 30 66 (?)
Sergeant, Tho. 3 31 86
Sherman, W.T. 3 31 76
Shoemaker, C.F. 2 28 7, 2 28 12, 2 28 13, 2 28 18, 2 28 20, 2 28 32, 2 28 34, 2 28 37, 2 28 38, 2 28 41
Shoup, Geo. L. 1 20 166
Shriver, Sargent 2 27 260
Sims, Wm. S. 3 31 32
Smith, Fred A. 1 21 181
Smith, Joseph 1 14 98
Smith, Mr. 1 2 14
Sothern, E. 3 31 63
Southard, Samuel 1 5 27
Spaulding, O.L. 2 28 8, 2 28 11, 2 28 14,15,21,23,26, 2 28 27-29,33
Stanley, Henry M. 3 31 61
Stanton, Edwin M. 1 12 86, 1 14 102, 1 16 122
Stefansson, Vilhjamur 2 26 233,34,36
Stevens, Tho. H. 1 16 127
Stevenson, Adlai 2 27 257
Stewart, Maj. Gen. David 2 30 29
Storey, Joseph 3 31 14
Stowe, Phineas 1 11 75
Street, Chas. 2 27 247
Stringham, S.H. 1 10 71, 1 15 141, 2 30 64 (?), 2 30 65 (?)
Sullivan, Algernon 3 31 45
Sullivan, Maj. Gen. 2 30 12
Taylor, Frank 2 29 9
Taylor, H.A. 2 28 16, 2 28 22 2 28 30,31,43,45 2 28 46,48
Tayman, C.E. 1 21 184
Tegetthoff, Wilhelm Von 1 16 120, 1 17 130
Tompkins, Daniel D. 3 31 16
Totten, Joseph G. 1 14 101
Townshend, E.F. 1 20 169
Truman, Harry S. 2 27 256
Truxton, Thomas 3 31 7
Tumulty, J.P. 2 25 223
Turner, Chas. 3 31 37
Tuttle, F. 2 28 33, 2 28 36, 2 28 39,43,44
Upshur, A.P. 1 7 46
Vaid, J.E. 1 15 116
Van Buren, Martin 1 10 72
Van Troup, Adml. 2 30 5
Vaughn, T. 3 31 44
Vernon, Adm. 2 30 32
Vespucci, Amerigo 2 30 53
Villard, O.E. 2 26 232
Von Humbolt 2 29 3
Voorhees, Ralph 1 5 26
Wakeham, Cyrus 2 27 10
Walker, R.J. 3 31 91
Walker, W. 1 8 51,52
Wallace, Henry A. 2 27 253
Warrington, Louis 1 9 58
Washington, Booker T. 2 25 220
Washington, George 1 2 10
Washington, Lewis 2 30 76
Washington, Martha 2 30 78
Watson, J.C. 2 28 5
Weaver, Adm. 1 3a 15A2
Webster, Daniel 1 8 52
Welles, Gideon 1 14 103
Welsh, C.F. 1 11 77
Wherry, Wm. 1 19 158, 2 24 207
Whingate, Capt. 1 3a 15
Whitesides, W. 2 29 1
Whittier, John G. 3 31 88
Wild, J.F. 2 28 35
Wilder, J.T. 1 20 165, 1 22 191
Willard, C.W. 1 17 135
Willcox, O.B. 1 21 190
William the Fourth 2 30 48
Willis, Nathaniel Parker 1 8 53, 1 12 84, 2 30 84
Wilson, Capt. 2 30 1
Wilson, James H. 1 20 164
Wilson, George S. 1 12 82, 1 14 99 1 15 109-13, 1 15 116, 1 15 117, 1 17 135, 1 18 143,44,46,47, 1 19 153,54,57-59, 1 20 162-64,66,68, 1 21 172-90, 1 22 191, 1 22 192,94-99, 1 23 200, 1 23 201,03,05, 2 24 206, 2 24 208-11,13,14, 2 29 7, 2 29 13, 3 31 60
Wilson, Miss Margaret S. 1 18 148, 2 25 216, 2 30 82
Wilson, Mrs. George S. 1 18 143, 2 24 207,212
Wilson, Woodrow 3 31 53
Wolfe, Dael 2 27 256
Wood, Commander Barney 2 30 74
Wothirspooh 1 21 187
Wyrick, O.D. 2 28 39
Zeitlin, J. 1 17 134
CONTAINER LIST
- 1. 1967, June,Bill of Benedict Arnold due from Samuel Huntington, debtor. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 2. 1769, July 9,Benjamin Franklin to [William Bartram] with notes on the verso by Bartram. ALS
- 3. 1769, July 9,Pos. photo of No. 2 above, 2 copies of letter and 1 of notes.
- 4. 1769, July 9,Typescript of letter in No. 2 above.
- 5. 1769, July 9,Negative photo of No. 2
- 6. 1776, Feb. 5,Elizabeth Franklin to Mrs. Bache., copy of letter. and photocopy
- 7. 1778, Feb. 14,Richard Bache to Benjamin Franklin (facs.)
- 8. 1782, Sept. 8,B. Franklin to David Hartley ALS (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 9. 1785, May 14,Alexander Hamilton to Wm. Duer ALS
- 10. 1785, May 16,Facs. ALS Geo. Washington to Fran. Hopkinson. N.B. by unknown.
- 11. 1786, Sept.7, A. Burr to []
- 12. 1805, Sept. 17,D[olley] P[ayne] Madison to Mrs. Harwood. ALS
- 13. [1805], Sept. 17,AL neg. photo (2 copies) of front side only of letter in No. 12.
- 14. [18]08, Mar. 3,T. J[efferson] to Mr. Smith ANS
- 15. 1812 - 1855Notes - mostly naval or from ship cruises. (Box 1, Folder 3a)
  - A. Correspondence of Brit. Naval Chronicle [notes]
    - 1. Naval transactions for the year 1823
    - 2. Corresp. Br. Naval Chronicle, Dec. 1, 1812; Nov. 1, 1812; Oct. 18, 1812;from report of [Capt. Whingate] to [Adm. Weaver].
    - 3. Capt. Gordon's report 25. Oct. 25, 1812.
    - 4. Corresp. Jan. 16, 1813; Jan. 28, 1813.
  - B. 1824Notes: 1st page ink crossed out. pencil corrections and revisions throughout. On board Constitution etc. a diary Oct. 1824 - July 26, 1825. Plan of Ancient Syracuse set in (hand done Map 20 Sicilian Caves. some ink revisions done in another hand.
  - C. 1827 April[diary?] (Box 1, Folder 3b)
  - D. [1832] July 20,log or diary - incomplete
  - E. 1832, Aug. 23-25(incomplete) log or diary
  - F. U.S. Schr Shark, March 1855
    - 1. Log - March 18-31
    - 2. Abstract kept on board the Shark, April 1836
    - 3. Remarks, April 1836
    - 4. Remarks relative to Salutes, April 1836
    - 5. April 1836,Donna Maria II's wedding
    - 6. April 1836,Anchored in the Tagas, etc.
- 16. 1812, Nov[] Memo. Isaac Hull and C[harles] Morris (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 17. 1813, Jan. 2,Aunt Louise [] to [] - in French ALS
- 18. 1813, Aug. 3,Jesse D. Elliott to Cox ALS
- 19. 1814, Feb. 25,Jesse D. Elliott to Cox ALS
- 20. 1816, May 4,James Monroe to [] ALS
- 21. 1819, Mar. 20,Wm. Bainbridge to A.A. Harwood ALS
- 22. 1820, Feb. 22,Samuel L. Brown to A.A. Harwood ALS
- 23. 1820, Mar. 28,J. Chauncey to commanding officer of the Hornet ALS
- 24. 1822, May 29,Wm. Bainbridge to A.A. Harwood ALS (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 25. 1823, Aug. 14,David Porter to Allen Harwood ALS
- 26. 1823, Aug. 14,Ralph Voorhees to Harwood ALS
- 27. 1824, July 26,Samuel Southard to Harwood ALS
- 28. 1825, April 16,John U. Farnham to Burnett -and enclosures., Photostats.
- 29. 1826, Sept. 3,Allen [Harwood] to Mrs. Sophia Bache ALS
- 30. 1827, Jan. 9,[] to Dear Aunt and Uncle-last part missing. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 31. 1928, Jan. 5,J. Chauncey, et. al. to Harwood ALS
- 32. 1831, April 11,Certificate signed by J.B. Gilpin DS
- 33. 1831, Aug. 11,Allen [Harwood] to Mrs. Bache ALS
- 34. 1833, June 18,August Davezac to Harwood (American lawyer and diplomat) ALS
- 35. 1833, July 3,Lt. Gen [Simon] [Bernas or Bernard] to Harwood ALS
- 36. 1834, Mar. 12,Andrew A. Harwood to Mrs. Bache ALS
- 37. 1834, July 14,Andrew A. Harwood to Mrs. Bache ALS
- 38. 1835, June 5,Andrew A. Harwood to Mrs. Bache ALS
- 39. 1835, Aug. 20,[A.A. Harwood] intended for Capt. Ingraham, contemporary copy
- 40. [1836], July 14,Andrew A. and Mrs. Harwood to Mrs. Bache ALS (Box 1, Folder 7)
- 41. [1836],Charles Babbage to Sr. John Hershel ALS
- 42. 1838, July 13,F. Arago to Lavalleé -in French ALS
- 43. 1839, Mar. 7,J. W. Dorr to Harwood ALS
- 44. 1839, April 1,E. Leslie to Harwood ALS
- 45. 1840, May 9,M.C. Perry to Harwood ALS
- 46. 1843, Mar. 11,A. P. Upshur to Harwood ALS
- 47. 1844, Mar. 30,Oath of Office of John C. Calhoun [Facs.?] (Box 1, Folder 8)
- 48. 1844, June 26,J. Y. Mason to Powell et. al. LS
- 49. 1844, June 27,Passport of Harwood signed by J. C. Calhoun
- 50. 1844, Sept. 11,Baron de Mackau to Harwood -in French ALS (French Admiral).
- 51. 1845, July. 5,J. C. Calhoun in 3rd person to W. Walker AL
  Missing as of 1985 Nov.
- 52. 1845, Mar. 11,D. Webster to Walker ALS
- 53. [1845] June 17,Nathaniel Parker Willis to J. Fenimore Cooper ALS
- 54. 1846, Oct. 30,J. Barron to L. M. Powell ALS
- 55. 1846, Nov. 7,D[avid] G. Farragut to Capt. L. Powell, together with a diagram of fixtures on the Decatur. ALS
- 56. 1847, June 9,William Duane to A. A. Harwood ALS (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 57. 1849, Feb. 12,J. Y. Mason to Harwood LS
- 58. 1850, June 8,Louis Warrington to Harwood LS
- 59. 1850, Nov. 6-7,D. G. Farragut to Harwood ALS
- 60. 1851, June 16,Henry W. Longfellow to Harwood (with part of envelope) ALS
- 61. 1852, Aug. 29,Andrew Harwood to Frank Harwood ALS
- 62. 1852, Oct. 18,John P. Kennedy to Harwood LS
- 63. 1852, Oct. 30,D. G. Farragut to Harwood ALS
- 64. 1852, Dec. 16,Napoleon III -in French ALS
- 65. 1853, Jan. 14,Charles Morris to Mrs. M. B. Harwood ALS (Box 1, Folder 10)
- 66. 1853, April 18,Andrew Harwood to Frank Harwood ALS
- 67. 1853, May 19 (May 31),Clip -in French - copy of a letter from Chancellor Count Nesselrode to Rechid-Pacha, minister of foreign affairs of La Porte, dated from St. Petersburg.
- 68. 1853, June 27,I. H. Hill to Harwood ALS
- 69. [1853], Oct. 30,John Graham to Harwood ALS
- 70. 1854, July 19,Franklin Harwood to Dear Sally ALS
- 71. 1854, Sept. 29,S. H. Stringham to A. A. Harwood LS
- 72. 1854, Nov. 22,M. Van Buren to Harwood ALS
- 73. 1855, Jan. 20,Charles Morris to Harwood ALS (Box 1, Folder 11)
- 74. 1855, March 30,John C. Long to Cmdr. Harwood ALS
- 75. 1855, June 30,Phineas Stowe - printed Welcome Hymn dedicated to A.A. Harwood, officers and crew of Cumberland.
- 76. 1855, Oct. 8,James C. Dobbin to Harwood LS
- 77. 1856, Aug. 19,Navy Dept. to A. A. Harwood - Appointment as Captain. s. C. F. Welsh
- 78. 1857, Mar. 1,Franklin Harwood to Dear Sally ALS
- 79. 1860, July 21,W. J. Duane to Harwood ALS
- 80. 1860, July 23, The Leaflet, political-literary sheet
- 81. 1861, Jan. 10,John A. Dalgren to President Lincoln. ALS - with comments of Lincoln, Jan. 10, 1861.ANS. [June?] (Box 1, Folder 12)
- 82. 1861, July 23,G. S. Wilson to his brother ALS
- 83. 1861, Nov. 17,Spencer F. Baird to Harwood ALS
- 84. 1861, Nov. 17,Nathaniel Parker Willis to Harwood ALS
- 85. 1862, Feb. 7,John A. McClernard to Harwood, (copy)
- 86. 1862, May 23,N. P. Banks to E. M. Stanton ALS
- 87. 1862, June 11,A. Lincoln to [Baird] ALS
- 88. 1862, Oct. 10,A[lbert] Haenel to [] French jurist -in French ALS
- 89. 1862, Oct. 23,John G. Nicolay to G. V. Fox, endorsed by Fox ALS
- 90. 1863, Jan. 10,S. F. Dupont to Harwood ALS (Box 1, Folder 13)
- 91. 1863, Feb. 24,Voucher: Survey of Military Defense - 1863 DS
- 92. 1863, Mar. 14,A. H. Foote to Harwood ALS
- 93. 1863, Mar. 17,John J. Cisco - treasury receipt
- 94. 1863, Mar. 27,Navy Dept. to A. A. Harwood, apptmt. as Commodore, s. Wm. Faxen
- 95. 1863, Mar. 28,Voucher: Survey of Military Defense, 1863, DS
- 96. 1863, April 4,William Luce, Memorandum DS, (2 copie)
- 97. 1863, May 7,Fd. d'Orleans ALS (Prince de Joinville)
- 98. 1863, June 1,Joseph Smith to Harwood ALS (Box 1, Folder 14)
- 99. 1863, July 13,Commission of Geo. S. Wilson s. O.P. Morton DS
- 100. 1863, Aug. 6,Richard B. Duane to Harwood ALS
- 101. 1863, Nov.[16],Joseph G. Totten to Harwood ALS
- 102. 1863, Nov. 20,A. Lincoln to Sec. of War endorsed by E. M. Stanton ALS
- 103. 1863, Nov. 21,Gideon Welles to Harwood ALS
- 104. 1863, Nov. 27,Edward Bates to Harwood ALS
- 105. 1863, Dec. 3,Edward Bates to Harwood ALS
- 106. 1863, Dec. 4,Edward Bates to Harwood ALS
- 107. [n.d.-after 1946]Frank Freidel, Red Tape in 1863: Bates and Lincoln ptd. art. frag. publ. in THE HISTORIAN; ptd. correspondence (Harwood) - #102, 103 104.
- 108. 1864, Feb. 17,Confederate States Note s. A. Cooke, and M. Allen (Box 1, Folder 15)
- 109. 1864, May 6,Discharge of Geo. S. Wilson s. Wm. Michael DS
- 110. 1864, May [16],Muster Roll - Geo. S. Wilson s. Henry
- 111. 1864, May 20,Discharge of Geo. S. Wilson, [J]ordan or Gordon-signed. DS
- 112. 1864, Aug. 6,Muster-out roll, Geo. S. Wilson (as 2nd Lieut.)
- 113. 1864, Aug. 6,Muster-in roll, Geo. S. Wilson (as 1st Lieut.)
- 114. 1864, Nov. 17,S. H. Stringham to Harwood LS
- 115. 1864,[], Memorandum on a courtmartial under Gen. Meade, unsigned
- 116, 1865, Aug. 8,Discharge of Geo. S. Wilson (1st lieut) s. J. G. Vaid DS
- 117. 1865,W. E. Doyle, History of the Seventeenth Indian Macon, Ga. copy belonging to Geo. S. Wilson
- 118. 1866, June 13,D. G. Farragut to Harwood ALS (Box 1, Folder 16)
- 119. 1866, June 28,D. G. Farragut to Harwood ALS
- 120. 1867, Feb. 7,Wilhelm Von Tegetthoff to Harwood ALS
- 121. 1967, April 3,T[homas] P. Rossiter to Harwood - artist ALS
- 122. 1867, July 2,Edwin M. Stanton to Geo. S. Wilson LS
- 123. 1867, Dec. 10,G. Garibaldi (facsimile?) ALS
- 124. 1868, Feb. 4,Charles Dickens to Harwood -with cvr. ALS
- 125. 1868, Feb. 7,ticket stub to Dickens Reading and photo of Dickens - verso photo T.R. Rossiter
- 126. 1868, April 30,ticket to Impeachment of the President
- 127. 1868, Dec. 27,[Thomas] H. Stevens to Harwood ALS
- 128. 1867-68,frag. of Confederate States Bond s.E. Bailey
- 129. 1869, Mar. 4,Ticket to the inauguration reception of Pres. Grant. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- 130. 1869, April 16,Wilhelm Von Tegetthoff to Harwood (with cvr) ALS
- 131. 1869, June 26,Oliver W. Holmes to Dr. Gould ALS
- 132. 1870, Jan. 22,Charles [] to [] PS. of ALS
- 133. 1870, April 29,Charles Leahr to [Mr. Rice] ALS
- 134. 1871, Sept. 23,J[acob] Zeilin to Harwood ALS
- 135. 1871, Dec. 16,Geo. [Wilson] to Dear Mother ALS from Ft. Hall, Idaho.
- 136. 1872, Jan. 1,Jere [Burnett] to [Sam Burnett] on U.S.S. California (from Hawaii) ALS
- 137. 1872, Oct. 30,Geo. William Curtis to C. W. Willard ALS
- 138. 1872,Joseph Henry, ptd. Eulogy on Prof. Alexander Dallas Bache Wn. GPO
- 139. 1872,ptd. art. The Ancient Vessel Found in the Parish of Tume, Norway, ANS S[teven] B. L[uce] to A. A. Harwood, author and translator unknown.
- 140. 1876, June 19,Pass to the Vatican issued to Harwood, stamped but unsigned (Box 1, Folder 18)
- 141. 1879, Feb. 25,Pres. and Mrs. [R. B.] Hayes to [A.A.] Harwood - Ptd. invitation to meet members of the Diplomatic Corps
- 142. 1879, Dec. 4,William Duane to Harwood ALS
- 143. 1880, Nov. 2,Geo. [S. Wilson] to Mrs. Geo. S. Wilson ALS
- 144. 1881, Mar. 23,ALS Geo. [S. Wilson] to wife [fiancee being relieved of duty with the Indians, transfers, death of Gen. Upton, a Forster murder.